Len Lester

Glendale, CA 91206 818-530-3486 lenster921@gmail.com Website LinkedIn

Experienced Full Stack Software Engineer with 10+ years of experience in web development and software applications. Proactive team player with keen insight at developing, managing, and scaling various initiatives across various multi-disciplinary environments. Proficient working within UI frameworks while ensuring technical usability and accessibility for positive user experiences. Willing to work remotely and relocate to New York or EU.

SKILLS

JavaScript • PHP • Node.JS • TypeScript • HTML • CSS • React • React Native • Next.JS • Tailwind • Redux • Zustand • DynamoDB • SQL • NoSQL • MongoDB • Webpack • Expo • Jest • Express • Jenkins • Docker • AWS

EXPERIENCE

Self Employed - Glendale, CA

01/2023 - Present

Mobile App Developer

Founded a company specializing in building and delivering various web and media solutions. Worked on end-to-end development of multiple mobile apps from inception to launch.

Key Competencies: TypeScript, React Native, Expo, Next.js, Tailwind, Zustand

Developed and shipped 3 separate React Native products to App Store and Google Play in under a month

- Leveraged many popular solutions with Expo, Reanimated, Gesture Handler, RevenueCat and AdMob
- Sped up development and unit testing with newer libraries like Zustand and Bun

Web Developer

Developed and managed Web3 projects utilizing Next.js, Typescript, and other contemporary web technologies. Composed tools and features with emphasis on intuitive user experience.

Key Competencies: TypeScript, Next.Js, Node.Js, HTML, CSS, Application Development

Acquired 2,500+ unique visitors within 3 months by creating web application for Doopmarketer

- Utilized component libraries like Chakra UI to display relevant information
- Extracted data from various sources using Ethers.JS in a Node.js serverless API

Age Of Learning, Inc. / ABCmouse.com - Glendale, CA Senior Software Engineer

10/2010 - 12/2022

03/2018 - 12/2022

Worked on all end-to-end development process updates, utilizing JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, Docker, and AWS services. Led implementation for adaptive learning engine, while ensuring compliance with company goals. Worked across teams on software and production implementation.

Key Competencies: JavaScript, PHP, MYSQL, HTML, CSS, AWS, Docker, Jenkins, Process Improvement

Accelerated productivity by 300% for Curriculum Specialist team

- Assessed strengths and weaknesses of potential databases such as Neptune Graph
- Generated backend API for migration of relational tables to graph database
- Partnered with curriculum specialists, creating tools for mapping taxonomies on ABCMouse

Saved \$100K per month by improving management of testing environments

- Created APIs to eliminate running EC2 instances and go live for limited times
- Built a frontend tool to allow product teams to remove or extend the life of their EC2 instances

Reduced development time 40% by producing faster, more efficient proprietary JavaScript framework

- Evaluated modern frameworks, to consider most important functionality and utilities
- Implemented proprietary JavaScript framework while ensuring compliance with needs of company
- Produced base component libraries for managing, organizing, and storing data

Decreased by 60% development time of content tools and money spent for dedicated engineers

- Programmed generic JavaScript/JSON form builder
- Surveyed project managers and product owners, gaining insight on additional form elements needed
- Built specific form elements to align with differing product needs

Software Engineer III 06/2015 - 03/2018

Developed various curriculum management tools, delivering helpful features and improvements with solid technical foundations. Composed framework for creating tools to facilitate the creation and deployment of content for products.

Key Competencies: JavaScript, PHP, MYSQL, HTML, CSS, AngularJS, User Experience, Process Improvement

Developed series of JavaScript tools to prepare new product launch

- Negotiated with product owners and project managers on gathering requirements for tools
- Designed suite of tools in preparation for launch of new product

Software Engineer II 04/2013 - 06/2015

Collaborated across teams to the ABCMouse's site from Flash/ActionScript to HTML/JavaScript, ensuring better end-to-end user experience. Designed tools that enabled animators to create 200+ high-quality animations for activities and games on revamped site.

Key Competencies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, ActionScrip/Flash, PHP, MYSQL, Research & Development, Mentoring

Optimized time and revenue by streamlining animation development process

- Developed tool to deconstruct Flash Animations into a images and metadata
- Created and optimized JavaScript Animation Player to allow for 1:1 animation
- Trained team of programmers on how to execute tools, along with troubleshooting needs

Flash Developer 10/2010 - 04/2013

Designed and implemented key features, increasing user engagement. Developed app's first iteration of Admin System, using JavaScript front-end PHP and MySQL back-end, resulting in faster release times and better user experience.

Key Competencies: Flash/ActionScript, PHP, MYSQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Web Development, Data Structures

Delivered content 200% faster with first iteration of Admin system

EDUCATION

California State University: Chico - Chico, CA Bachelor Of Arts - Linguistics